<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>science communication on Mindy Tran&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://mindy-tran.github.io/Mindy_Portfolio/tags/science-communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in science communication on Mindy Tran&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://mindy-tran.github.io/Mindy_Portfolio/tags/science-communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Concussion Biosensor</title>
      <link>https://mindy-tran.github.io/Mindy_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mindy-tran.github.io/Mindy_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description> UOregon iGEM Team at the 2022 iGEM Jamboree. Paris, FR. Link to iGEM Team Website Link to Team Twitter&#xA;Science Communication Lead for the University of Oregon team to compete in the iGEM Competition for Synthetic Biology Bronze Medal Team 2022 Prototyped a rapid and low-cost diagnostic device to detect concussion (mTBI) biomarkers collaborating with a team of 12 cross-disciplinary undergraduate students Presented to a panel of interdisciplinary judges at the iGEM Jamboree 2022, an international synthetic biology competition Launched and managed the team&amp;rsquo;s Twitter page leveraging comparative review and content campaigning, boosting the visibility of our concussion research attaining 300+ social media interactions from researchers and biotech leaders Created the team&amp;rsquo;s promotional video communicating the team&amp;rsquo;s biosensor research leveraging storytelling to engage technical and non-technical audiences Spearheaded talent acquisition of undergraduate scientists to join the team through class visits, presentations, and recruitment videos </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
